Mobile- 613-796-1810, email: robinshrestha.developer@gmail.com

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

PROFILE SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with passion for code and more than two years of experience in Web applications and software development. Demonstrated proficiency in software development skills and research skills to find the solutions to the problems. Delivered high quality results in fast paced environment within project time framework.

KEY SKILLS

- Create new code and troubleshoot existing code
- Write, develop and review test plans and test cases
- Document, reproduce and resolve defects.
- Strong Knowledge and experience of Web development using HTML, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React, Node.js, MongoDB.
- Knowledge of object-oriented programing and application development tools using Python, Java, Java Swing, XML, VBA and knowledge of Computer Architecture and virtualization.
- Quantitative and qualitative analytical ability
- Knowledge of Database Management (RDBMS) using MS Access, PostgreSQL, SQL server and Oracle.
- Experience with online research. Advance user of Statistical Software SPSS. About six researches completed
- Excellent documentation, communication and teamwork skills
- Self-Starter and working on own initiative

TECHNICAL PORTFOLIO

Web Development	HTML, PHP, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, XML, JSP, Node.js, React, bootstrap		
Other Programming Knowledge	C#, Java SE 8, Java EE 8, Python, Visual Basic. NET, VBA for Access,		
	Hibernate		
Mobile Development	Android Studio		
CMS	Wordpress		
Database Knowledge	Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, SQLite, Access		
Integrated Development	Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, PyCharm, Android Studio Windows, Mac OS, Linux -Ubuntu		
Operating Systems			
Office Tools	Microsoft Office, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, SharePoint,		
	OpenOffice		

Languages:

English- fluent, French- Intermediate, Nepali- fluent and Hindi- fluent,

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES AND WORK ACHIEVEMENTS

Freelance Web Developer

September 2021- till now

Oasis Non-Profit Project work, Ottawa

- Developing Oasis website for a non-profit organization using Visual Studio Code and PostgreSQL.
- Designed different pages, added webpage language support (localization) and used JSON, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React-Bootstrap, React Router, React, Hooks, Redux, Node.js.
- Designed and created database and tables and worked with Express and Axios to link with the backend database.
- Worked with image editing and video editing to adjust to webpage.

QA Engineer

May 2019 to May 2020

Visioneer Canada Inc, Ottawa

- Reviewed quality documents and designed network documents
- Created comprehensive and well-structured test plans and test cases
- Used Microsoft Excel and Word for testing the window scanner application in various versions of Windows and Mac computers
- Created various networks and tested the application and recorded in OneNote

Robin Shrestha

Mobile- 613-796-1810, email: robinshrestha.developer@gmail.com

• Worked to develop application for Scanners using C# in Visual Studio 2017.

Software Development Algonquin College Project

January 2018 to April 2018

Algonquin College, Ottawa

- Programming software WritePub for online eBook reader file maker and converter
- Wrote, modified, integrated and tested software code for the application with a technical agile development and coordinated with clients
- Used node.js, java script, html programming languages, used GitHub in Visual Studio Code

Software Developer/Analyst Coop

Sept 2018 to December 2018

Canada Revenue Agency, Government of Canada, Ottawa

- Worked for Integras Corporate Software of Canada Revenue Agency
- Used Java, XML and Java Swing coding languages
- Developed various Gui applications
- Used Data input validation techniques
- Completed various testings
- Got Scrum agile training

Software Developer Coop-

May 2018 to August 2018

Nokia Alcatel-Lucent – Ottawa, Kanata

- Developed a software Application for Nokia Pre-Sales Department
- Used Visual Basic programming language, SharePoint Server Lists, Microsoft Access
- Developed new techniques for Jira Application Data to be exported as excel files and imported to the application
- Developed tracking mechanism for users and their data input from SharePoint online

ITP Human Resources Associate (Volunteer Position)

May 2016 to Dec 2016

Rideau Rockcliffe Community Resource Centre-Ottawa, Canada

- Managed computer files and sorted according to the department needs.
- Reviewed Performance Evaluation process
- Analyzed recruitment process including consideration of relevant legislation
- Tracked and monitored administrative / management documents

Human Resource Admin

August 2009 to Feb 2016

Caritas Nepal – Lalitpur, Nepal

- Standardized recruitment process by programming in MS Excel and Ms. Access
- Prepared and conducted performance research, completed performance evaluation using SPSS and online survey, salary review using various data analysis methods.
- Offered training about MS. Excel to staffs.
- Recruitment, Training and Payroll management

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Security Guard/Receptionist (Part-time)

October 2020 to till now.

Iron Horse Security- 3590 Rivergate way, Ottawa

- Checking entry and exit, handling and communicating during emergencies.
- Issuing parking permit and booking visitors entry.
- Security cameras surveillance and looking after any rule violations,

VOLUNTEER WORK

- Volunteered in Pinecrest Food Bank and as Office support staff.
- Algonquin College Student Representative- Computer Programmer- 4th Semester

Mobile- 613-796-1810, email: robinshrestha.developer@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Diploma in Web Development

2021-2022

Lighthouse Lab, Toronto

https://www.lighthouselabs.ca/

 Course Highlights: JavaScript & Node.js, Databases & Data Modeling, HTML, CSS and More, Software Architecture, React JS, Ruby on Rails

Diploma in Computer Programming

Jan 2017 - April 2019

Algonquin College - Ottawa

http://www.algonquincollege.com/sat/program/computer-programmer/

 Course Highlights: Web Programming, Java Programming, IT Project Management, Database Programming, Python Programming, Computer Architecture, Network Programming, Mobile Graphical Interface Programming, Business Intelligence and Data Analytics

Bachelor of Business in Management |

2013

Tribhuvan University, Nepal

• Courses: Econometrics, SPSS Data Analysis, Finance

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

•	Modern React with Redux Certification	2021	
•	Node with React: Full Stack Web Development		2021
•	Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp	2021	
•	Agile Scrum Training for Computer Programming	2018	
•	Occupational Health and Safety (Ontario), Accessibility (AODA), First Aid	2016	
•	Business and Finance Communication Course- Algonquin College	2016	
•	Computer Software: MS Office, MS Access	2004-2008	

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS COMPLETED

Reverb Project

July 2022 to Aug.2022

Reverb project is a Spotify clone application where user can login with Spotify user id. The songs details are recorded in its own database. Users can view library songs, create playlists and listen to songs.

Interview Scheduler May 2022 to June 2022

With this application, a student can create, edit and delete interview appointments. It uses React, custom hooks, PostgreSQL database. The application to API server over HTTP by JSON format. The development follows the Test Driven Development-individual component testing and End-to-End testing.

Lighthouse BNB Apr. 2022 to May 2022

A database application project developed as a part of Lighthouse Labs Web development course.

Tweeter Project Mar. 2022 to Mar. 2022

Tweeter is a single page app built with HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery, AJAX, Express with tweeting functionality.

<u>FinyApp</u> Feb. 2022 to Feb. 2022

TinyApp is a full stack web application built with Node and Express that allows users to shorten long URLs like bit.ly website do. This project has an HTTP Server that handles requests from browser(client).

Oasis website Sept. 2021 to Current

Project going on Oasis Non-profit website.

RESEARCH COMPLETED

Comparative Study of Hard Disk Drives in Personal Computers

Analysis of Parking Permit issued in Vancouver downtown (Business Intelligence)

2018

Website: https://robinshrestha.github.io/robinshresthacv/index.html
Youtube: EasyLife Technology, mrrobslife@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/robinshrestha12